One very important thing that I noticed
when working with AI is that even if you
give enough context for an agent to work
on a single task, they still have no
idea about your project. So maybe what
we're going to see from now on is I do a
quick prototype, let the agent ingest
all the context, not just from me, but
also from the code itself automatically
build it, throw it away, and if we still
have context window, we start from
scratch in a clean architect to a clean
domain driven design. Really nicely done
and maybe this result is going to be
better on the second try.
>> Let's trigger people. Alex, are you
ready to trigger the audience?
>> Yes.
>> Let's trigger the audience. Does Scrum
even have a role in this future?
>> This is a tough question.
[Music]
Uh I know a lot of people are putting a
lot of effort into becoming
uh good scrum masters, good agile
coaches. And while this is very
important when working with humans, we
really need to
think at refactoring the processes the
way same way you refactor code.
>> So when you refactor code, you don't
throw away everything. You just look at
what's working and try to improve it and
to streamline it and simplify it. And
this is what we need to do also with
>> scrum or all all these agile processes
that are built for humans to work in a
certain way. But now suddenly we have
infinite bandwidth. We have different
processes like we said like different uh
deliverables checkpoints where the
humans have to review this and it has to
be much much faster than waiting two
weeks to have the uh the scrum review
where we present the the output to the
stakeholders.
>> We we might need two three reviews per
day in the future. So what would you say
are like the key AI scrum measurements
or or flags we need to kind of like
raise at various points? What what
what's the equivalent?
>> So what are the core fundamental uh
features of scrum? It allows you to have
uh certain deliverables in a certain
amount of time and to coordinate between
teams and stakeholders this uh
deliverable so that you can verify if
you should proceed or you have to change
things. And maybe what we can learn from
from scrum is this like create AI uh
checkpoints where sort of all of the AIs
that worked in parallel the whole night
before they reach the same point maybe
they handshake between each other and
they say okay now we need the human in
the loop
>> and afterwards we can proceed with
another batch of parallel agents but not
before the agent has validated. It's
almost it's almost an AI scrum that then
introduces a human at the right time.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah. Very interesting.
>> We're going to jump into the second half
of our conversation, but first a quick
shout out to AI Native DevCon. 2 days of
hands-on sessions, deep dives, and
honest conversations about what it means
to build AI native software. November
18th and 19th in New York or join
virtually from anywhere. Tickets and
details at a native.io/devcon.
See you there. Um let's talk a little
bit about the futures. Let's get crystal
ball and kind of say okay 6 months time,
12 months time, maybe even longer. What
do you expect to see I guess both in and
around agents or specs? What are the
major changes that you foresee in
software development uh in and around
those two areas? So we have to look a
little bit back to understand where the
curve is coming from. Yeah.
>> So, uh, cloud code was, uh, released
somewhere in March, April,
>> which is insane in it.
>> And this is like just few months ago.
And now we already have few iterations
of it and can run in parallel, can use
nested agents. It's so powerful. And if
I think that in 6 months, it's going to
be even more powerful given that we're
on an exponential curve. It's very hard
to predict where we're going to go. But,
uh, the what are the fundamentals? The
fundamentals are AI agents that are
becoming more and more a hub, a central
hub that can decide what to do based on
the human interaction.
>> Mhm.
>> So
uh I expect them to run completely uh 24
by7.
>> Yep. So I don't expect you to have to
run code and then you give him a task
and then you stop it and then you start
with a fresh session. Uh so uh I don't
expect you to have to start clothe uh
give him a task finish the task clo
close close him and start it start a new
task in another session. I expect to
have a persistent agent that runs 24 by7
that is your central hub. M
>> this agent should be your input point
should keep a context window that has an
understanding of what you need to
achieve as a human but then it will use
sub agents to actually solve the tasks
and it should keep his own context
window as small as possible so that can
coordinate sort of a team lead of of
agents basically that can spawn agents
when needed and this agent can also be
proactive and we saw this uh uh recently
with some CHP features where you get
proactive information every morning that
are relevant for you and I think agents
are can do the same but better because
agent can use tool uh can call tools can
connect to uh other sources of
information and can maybe get trained on
your own uh data and then they can
actually actively work on things that
you can delegate to him or he can come
to you and say hey you should uh prepare
for the birthday of your wife that's
coming next month. Uh I think it's a
good moment to start looking at presents
or organizing a party.